Guide to the John Lovari Collection of the Staff of the New-York Historical Society Organizing Records WAG.169
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
John Lovari Collection of the Staff of the New-York Historical Society Organizing Records
1979-1997
1979-1980
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Lovari, John A.
WAG.169
0.5 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box
In 1979 the staff of the New-York Historical Society began an organizing drive with District 65, United Automobile Workers of America. Victory in the union elections led to contract negotiations, and the staff conducted a six month strike before signing a collective bargaining agreement in 1980. This collection contains newspaper clippings, photographs, minutes from the negotiating committee, copies of contracts, and leaflets.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged in alphabetical order by topic.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains newspaper clippings, photographs, minutes from the negotiating committee, copies of contracts, and leaflets.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by John A. Lovari in 2000. The accession number 2000.029 is associated with this gift.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
In 1979 the staff of the New-York Historical Society began an organizing drive with District 65, United Automobile Workers of America. Victory in the union elections led to contract negotiations later in the same year. The negotiations were unsuccessful, and the staff conducted a six month strike before signing a collective bargaining agreement in 1980.
John Lovari was a reference librarian at the New-York Historical Society, head of the negotiating committee, and after an agreement was reached, a shop steward.
Library employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Labor disputes -- New York (State) -- New York.; Distributive, Processing, and Office Workers of America. District 65; New-York Historical Society; Lovari, John A.
- Clippings, 1979-1980, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Collective Bargaining Agreements, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence: New-York Historical Society, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence: Staff of the New-York Historical Society, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Federation of Special Police and Law Enforcement Officers, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Financial and Salary Schedules, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Leaflets, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Meeting Minutes, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Museum Labor Relations, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Notes and Revisions, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Picket Schedules, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Photographs, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)